<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Vasileios Tsakalos</title><description>Projects, Services &amp; Posts by Vasileios Tsakalos</description><link>https://vtsakalos.com/</link><item><title>Build a kafka application in Python and Go</title><link>https://vtsakalos.com/posts/oop_ml/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://vtsakalos.com/posts/oop_ml/</guid><description>Dive into the intersection of Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) and machine learning in our blog. Explore how OOP principles enhance the development and deployment of machine learning models, leveraging encapsulation, inheritance, and polymorphism to build scalable and efficient solutions.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 08:29:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Feature engineering for Machine Learning</title><link>https://vtsakalos.com/posts/feature-engineering-f-machine-learning/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://vtsakalos.com/posts/feature-engineering-f-machine-learning/</guid><description>Dive into the art of &apos;Feature Engineering for Machine Learning&apos; with this comprehensive article, where we delve into the crucial process of crafting effective features to enhance model performance. Through insightful explanations and practical Python implementations, learn essential techniques to preprocess and engineer features, empowering your machine learning models with the ability to extract meaningful insights from data.</description><pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 08:58:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Build a kafka application in Python and Go</title><link>https://vtsakalos.com/posts/kafka-py-go/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://vtsakalos.com/posts/kafka-py-go/</guid><description>Explore Kafka&apos;s fundamentals and implementation nuances, from theoretical underpinnings to hands-on coding examples, learn to leverage Kafka&apos;s distributed streaming platform effectively in both Python and Go environments.</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 18:59:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Information retrieval with Python</title><link>https://vtsakalos.com/posts/information-retrieval-w-python/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://vtsakalos.com/posts/information-retrieval-w-python/</guid><description>Explore the fundamentals of information retrieval through our detailed tutorial, coupled with practical Python implementation. Gain theoretical insights and apply them directly in Python, enhancing your understanding and proficiency in this essential field.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 20:10:32 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>